BHUPESH YADAV

(785) 408-3189 bhupeshy@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An accomplished customer engineering leader in Payments and Fintech having both Technical and Soft skills. Experience in the full life cycle of the software design/development process including requirements gathering & definition, technical pre-sales, proof of concept, design, development, testing, performance and maintenance. Experienced at hiring and mentoring teams of managers, leads and engineers.

A start up enthusiast, worked in 2 successful startups that got acquired by Fortune 500 companies. I wrote my thoughts on Finextra here - https://www.finextra.com/bloggers/130168

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Advisory Fiserv Inc. 08/2017 - Present

Bulge Bracket Client Implementations, Instant Payments Engine Development & Delivery

- Manage critical client implementation spanning across the globe with millions of daily payments (real time, high value, ACH) with 99% STP rates.
- Leading the critical efforts of key client Deutsche Bank to remove legacy US and EU based solutions and use the new EPS payments solution providing new offerings for the client and resulting in achieving payments modernization and regulatory changes.
- Leading the multi-million dollar efforts of banks to switch to ISO20022 MX changes happening across the globe for SWIFT and HV clearings like CHAPS, Target2, EBA.
- Managing and mentoring a global team of 10+ Solution Architects and Engineers on day-to-day
 implementation activities for EU, APAC and US implementations for clients like Deutsche Bank, JPMC,
 Sterling, TBK, Eastern Bank resulting in successful client implementations and new revenue offerings.
- Guiding the teams across clients for solutions ranging from instant schemes to new payments initiatives across the globe spanning 50+ clearing schemes.

Engineering Manager/Sr. Solutions

Architect Dovetail Systems 01/2014 – 08/2017

- Implemented first ever Instant Payments Implementation for CEFTS SL clearing for Deutsche Bank creating another revenue stream for the company. This also laid the foundation for other instant clearing schemes like UPI India, SEPA Instant Payments (EU), TCH RTP (US).
- Executed a complex hybrid project for Deutsche Bank where components from both Dovetail and Deutsche Bank got integrated for the Galileo programme which contributed 25% to the company revenue.
- Established a good framework to share details about the hybrid solution establishing trust in the project and resulting in 25% reduction in integration issues found and going live within a year.
- · Hired, managed and mentored an ever increasingly team of Architects and Engineers.

Technical Architect Dovetail Systems 12/2009 – 12/2013

- Led the POC and Implementation work for one of the biggest clients Deutsche Bank.
- Led the implementation for the ACSS Clearing work resulting in timely and quality delivery for a Desjardins client in Canada.
- Worked on designs and implementations for key projects and clients like Treasury Data Integrator to report AML transactions, ZABSV and ZASAM (South Africa) clearing implementations.

EDUCATION

B.Tech Computer Science	Kurukshetra University	09/1998 – 06/2002
Diploma Advanced Computing	C-DAC Bangalore	01/2003 - 02/2004

Skills, Languages and Technologies